AKASH NIMARE

SUMMARY

I'm a self taught full stack web developer living in Surat, India. I love to build and design things.

I have experience in creating cross platform desktop applications, website backends, rest-api, chrome extensions, user experience and visual design. I have worked extensively in teams and alone.

EMPLOYMENT

Dropbox Remote

Contract Software Developer · May 2016 to Current I am currently working with Dropbox. Contributing to their open source project Zulip. Zulip is a open source group chat application.

HackerRank Bangalore

Software Developer' Intern • May 2015 to Jul 2015 Worked on performance and front-end projects. I built a dashboard to monitor and measure their site performance in realtime.

Hack InOut

Lead Organizer · 2015 to Current

InOut is one of India's largest student run hackathon. Twice a year the best developers, designers and hardware enthusiasts from across India gather at NIT Surat to innovate and build on an idea.

PROJECTS

Zulip Desktop Client

It's a cross platform app built on top of Electron and node.js.

Cyberoma Desktop Client

Cross-platform app for Linux, Mac and Windows.

hackinout.co

Hackathon website built for InOut.

Github AMA

A better way to read GitHub AMA. Built using Angularjs, GitHub Api.

Vehiclesearch

Rest api for M.P. Vehicle Registration data.

Gogit

Node module to create/add/commit/push to github in a single command.

CONTACT

- **Svnitakash@gmail.com**
- **Q** akashnimare.in
- **4** +91 8000 167 937
- ♥ H-13 SVNIT, Surat Gujarat(India)
- **f** meakaakka
- ♥ meakaakka
- in /akashnimare
- akashnimare

EDUCATION

Sardar Valllabhbhai National Institute of Technology, Surat

Integrated M.Sc. Applied Physics 2017

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES:: Proficient with Javascript, node, Python, Css, Sass

TOOLS AND SYSTEM: Proficient with Linux, Git, Bash, Angular, Bootstrap, Jquery, D3, js, Electron, Chrome Extension

OTHER AREAS OF INTEREST: Open source, Web scraping, Rest Api

ACTIVITIES

WebDev Labs · Founder and Head

Nov 2012 to Current

Founded WebDev Labs with two friends in first semester and have been working altruistically to help my fellow juniors and batch-mates and to build a developer ecosystem.

E - cell · Founder and Coordinator,

Mar 2013 to Feb 2015

Founded Entrepreneurship Development Cell - NIT Surat which is aligned towards developing entrepreneurial eco-system in the institute by nurturing young people with bright ideas.

Sparsh · Web Designing Coordinator Mar 2013 to Feb 2014

Lead and developed website for Sparsh 2013, Sparsh 2014. "Sparsh" is NIT Surat's annual cultural fest.